Contact

6469469909 (Mobile) manbir.pahwa@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mspahwa (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Data Modeling
Business Intelligence Tools
Business Intelligence (BI)

Certifications

AWS Training Certificate
Big Data on AWS

Apache Spark with Scala Training for Big Data Solutions

Manbir Pahwa

Data Architect at NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital Flushing, New York

Summary

Extensive IT experience building architecture for different data domains including financial and health analytics and data warehouses. Self-motivated and always come up with creative solutions to enhance system functionality. An excellent team player and a mentor with the capability to work across different users group, including stakeholders, business users, project managers, and peers. Adaptable to new technologies and apply innovation to existing products.

Experience

NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital Data Architect February 2017 - Present Manhattan, New York

NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital Technical Specialist June 2016 - February 2017 (9 months) Manhattan, New York

Cleveland Clinic 8 years 11 months

Enterprise Business Intelligence Database Developer November 2012 - April 2016 (3 years 6 months) Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

Programmer Developer
June 2007 - November 2012 (5 years 6 months)
Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

RMSystems
Research Engineer
March 2004 - June 2006 (2 years 4 months)

Chandigarh Area, India

Education

The University of British Columbia

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science · (1996 - 2000)